because I want to ask you a couple of questions. I think many here, and in general in Western countries, would agree with your statement about analysis of democratic systems becoming dysfunctional, but at the same time, many would kind of find unsettling the thought that there is an unelected authority that, without any form of oversight or consultation, decides what the national interest is. What is the mechanism in the Chinese model that allows people to say, actually, the national interest as you defined it is wrong? EXL: You know, Frank Fukuyama, the political scientist, called the Chinese system "responsive authoritarianism." It's not exactly right, but I think it comes close. So I know the largest public opinion survey company in China, okay? Do you know who their biggest client is? The Chinese government. Not just from the central government, the city government, the provincial government, to the most local neighborhood districts. They conduct surveys all the time. Are you happy with the garbage collection? Are you happy with the general direction of the country? So there is, in China, there is a different kind of mechanism to be responsive to the demands and the thinking of the people. My point is, I think we should get unstuck from the thinking that there's only one political system -- election, election, election -- that could make it responsive. I'm not sure, actually, elections produce responsive government anymore in the world. (Applause) BG: Many seem to agree. One of the features of a democratic system is a space for civil society to express itself. And you have shown figures about the support that the government and the authorities have in China. But then you've just mentioned other elements like, you know, big challenges, and there are, of course, a lot of other data that go in a different direction: tens of thousands of unrests and protests and environmental protests, etc. So you seem to suggest the Chinese model doesn't have a space outside of the Party for civil society to express itself. EXL: There's a vibrant civil society in China, whether it's environment or what-have-you. But it's different. You wouldn't recognize it. Because, by Western definitions, a so-called civil society has to be separate or even in opposition to the political system, but that concept is alien for Chinese culture. For thousands of years, you have civil society, yet they are consistent and coherent and part of a political order, and I think it's a big cultural difference. BG: Eric, thank you for sharing this with TED. EXL: Thank you.
porque quiero hacerte un par de preguntas. Creo que muchos aquí y en general en los países occidentales, estarán de acuerdo con tu afirmación sobre el análisis de que los sistemas democráticos se están volviendo disfuncionales, pero al mismo tiempo, muchos encontrarán inquietante pensar que hay una autoridad no elegida que, sin ningún tipo de supervisión o consulta, decide lo que es el interés nacional. ¿Cuál es el mecanismo en el modelo chino que permite a las personas decir, en realidad, el interés nacional como Uds. lo definieron está mal? EXL: Sabes, Frank Fukuyama, el politólogo, llamaba al sistema chino "autoritarismo sensible". No es exactamente cierto, pero está cerca. Conozco a la compañía más grande de encuestas de opinión pública en China, ¿de acuerdo? ¿Sabes quién es su cliente más grande? El gobierno chino. Desde el gobierno central, el gobierno de la ciudad, el gobierno provincial, hasta la mayoría de los distritos locales. Llevan a cabo encuestas todo el tiempo. ¿Estás contento con la recolección de basura? ¿Estás contento con la dirección general del país? Así que, en China, hay otro tipo de mecanismo para ser sensible a las demandas y el pensamiento de la gente. Mi punto es, creo que deberíamos despegarnos del pensamiento de que hay solo un sistema político, elecciones, elecciones, elecciones... que puede que sea sensible. No sé, en realidad, las elecciones producen gobiernos sensibles en el mundo ya. (Aplausos) BG: Muchos parecen estar de acuerdo. Una de las características de un sistema democrático es un espacio para la sociedad civil para expresarse. Y has mostrado las cifras sobre el apoyo que el gobierno y las autoridades tienen en China. Pero luego solo mencionaste otros elementos como, ya sabes, grandes retos y hay, por supuesto, un montón de otros datos que van en una dirección diferente: decenas de miles de disturbios y protestas y protestas por el medio ambiente, etc. Así que parece que sugieren que el modelo chino no tiene un espacio fuera del partido para que la sociedad civil pueda expresarse. EXL: Hay una sociedad civil vibrante en China, sea el ambiente o lo que quieras. Pero es diferente. No puedes reconocerlo. Porque, en las definiciones occidentales, una llamada sociedad civil tiene que estar separada o incluso en oposición al sistema político, sin embargo, ese concepto es ajeno para la cultura china. Durante miles de años, ha existido una sociedad civil, que aún es consistente y coherente y forma parte de un orden político, y creo esta una gran diferencia cultural. BG: Eric, gracias por compartir esto con TED. EXL: Gracias.